<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The wel_ko blog | A blog about reading, writing and the like.</title>
    <description>A blog where I review books, try to report on my progress as a writer and generally add other ramblings that come to mind.</description>
    <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://thewelkoblog.xyz/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 21:39:48 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 21:39:48 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Peter Clines - Dead Men Can't Complain and Other Stories</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I like the stories Peter Clines writes. That’s why I’ve read all the Ex-Heroes books, Threshold stories and why I’ve got his newest book - &lt;em&gt;Dead Moon&lt;/em&gt; - very high on my priority list.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Most of these stories are funny. Predictable, but funny. I really like the opener. It got me in a flow, so that I wanted to keep reading all the stories in this collection.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For an ex-heroes fan, this book is great. There’s even an ex-related short story in there. But sadly enough, most of the stories are quite the same. In the end, the plot of...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 21:25:37 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/peter-clines-dead-men-cant-complain-and-other-stories/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/peter-clines-dead-men-cant-complain-and-other-stories/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>C.J. Tudor - The Hiding Place</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the novel, I was getting a bit annoyed. The author writes to get a maximum amount of suspense, and that was getting on my nerve. Mostly because in the beginning, you don’t really know what is going on. You just know that Joe is back in town because of some things that happened. When details about the backstory became clear, the story got a lot better.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I very much like how Joe changes throughout the book. From the man he is, to the man he wants to be, to whom he really is. The part about...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 19:40:42 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/cj-tudor-the-hiding-place/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/cj-tudor-the-hiding-place/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gregg Hurwitz - Out of the Dark</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Evan Smoak is back for his greatest mission so far. Can he do the impossible and kill the man responsible for everything that happened in the previous books? And what’s special about his first mission in 1997? We find out in this book, but Orphan X needs to make sure he doesn’t get killed in the process. This time, it’s Orphan A who’s hunting him.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Out of the Dark&lt;/em&gt; is another great addition to the already amazing Orphan X universe. Not only is it fast-paced, full of the right details and finished with a nice touch of humour, it’s also...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 15:50:23 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/gregg-hurwitz-out-of-the-dark/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/gregg-hurwitz-out-of-the-dark/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Karen M. McManus - Two Can Keep a Secret</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Although the titles both have numbers, this book has nothing to do with the previous book from the same author. Instead, this story has its own characters, places and plot. Which is a good thing, really!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are characters in this book that have been on my nerve since page one. Some characters are in this book to fill the pages, not to add to the story. What a shame and a waste of time for all of us.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I don’t really like how Ellery develops through this book. There’s nothing that lifts her to a higher level or makes...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 14:35:54 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/karen-m-mcmanus-two-can-keep-a-secret/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/karen-m-mcmanus-two-can-keep-a-secret/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I've Read - January 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;lab-rats&quot;&gt;Lab Rats&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;I started my year of reading books with a non-fiction book about current company cultures. &lt;em&gt;Lab Rats&lt;/em&gt; discusses what’s wrong with current companies and what needs to change.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1529544098l/38901702.jpg&quot; class=&quot;monthly-summary-summary&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you want to read an interesting book about job security in current times and things like that, pick up this book. It’s a fun read!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;an-anonymous-girl&quot;&gt;An Anonymous Girl&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;An interesting read that I was able to pick up, is &lt;em&gt;An Anonymous Girl&lt;/em&gt;. The book was released in the first week of January so it was really quite new when I got my hands...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 15:07:56 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-january-2019/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-january-2019/</guid>
        
        <category>2019</category>
        
        
        <category>Monthly Summary</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Greer Hendricks &amp; Sarah Pekkanen - An Anonymous Girl</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of these books that was recently released, is &lt;em&gt;An Anonymous Girl&lt;/em&gt;. It’s written by two authors and you can see that, but not too much. The problem with two authors is that the two writing styles need to align throughout the book. I think these ladies did a wonderful thing in that regard.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of suspense in this book, which is good for a psychological suspense novel I guess. The way it’s written, it always leaves you wanting to read more. There’s some action but most of the story is really about thinking and making tough decisions.&lt;/p&gt;...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 19:47:51 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/greer-hendricks-sarah-pekkanen-an-anonymous-girl/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/greer-hendricks-sarah-pekkanen-an-anonymous-girl/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dan Lyons - Lab Rats</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Dan Lyons makes a great speech about how current tech companies are ruining the industry for not only employees, but for everyone. He makes good arguments on why we should stop just adopting the so-called newest tips and tricks about modern management.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I agree that we should stop firing people for no real reason. That we should go back to a company style where we would check whether someone who isn’t right for the job might be right for another one. I know some people who have had the same unfair fate.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Dan Lyons was going for a great book,...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 20:42:18 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/dan-lyons-lab-rats/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/dan-lyons-lab-rats/</guid>
        
        <category>Non-fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I've Read - December 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;brief-cases&quot;&gt;Brief Cases&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;I am a huge fan of the Dresden Files. I’ve been reading these books and stories since 2016 and I can’t wait for book 16 to come out. Jim Butcher posts some updates on his website now and then, and lately he’s given me hope that &lt;em&gt;Peace Talks&lt;/em&gt; might be out near the end of the year if not at the beginning of 2020. I really hope so!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1513644037l/12183815.jpg&quot; class=&quot;monthly-summary-summary&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Before you read this book, you should read up on the other Dresden Files books. They are all so good. Please go and pick up...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 15:14:10 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-december-2018/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-december-2018/</guid>
        
        <category>2018</category>
        
        
        <category>Monthly Summary</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Year in Books - 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-numbers&quot;&gt;The numbers&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;This year I have surpassed my biggest hopes, in terms of reading, that is. My reading challenge was set to 60 books. This choice was made because I was able to read 50 in 2017 and I knew I would have more time in 2018. And then it was September or October, and suddenly I had read 60 books! And so I adjusted my goal, but only for myself, to 75. And I nailed it! &lt;strong&gt;75&lt;/strong&gt; books is where the counter ticked off in 2018!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As I’ve read 24 books more in 2018 than in 2017, it’s...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 11:15:14 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/my-year-in-books-2018/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/my-year-in-books-2018/</guid>
        
        
        <category>My Year in Books</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jay Anson - The Amityville Horror</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I started reading the book with that one line in mind. And if you do that, it gets creepy fast. There’s a moment where I just had to double check that this wasn’t real and of course, it wasn’t. But still, I had the feeling I shouldn’t read this book late at night. Or in the dark.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What more do you want from a horror book? Good characters maybe? What this book lacks in character development it makes up in rapid horrifying events that will get your brain working over them. There’s not enough time to really live with the...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 13:09:38 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/jay-anson-the-amityville-horror/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/jay-anson-the-amityville-horror/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jim Butcher - Brief Cases</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Just like &lt;em&gt;Side Jobs&lt;/em&gt;, this collection allows us to experience the Dresdenverse from different perspectives. Given all the stories that are already there, Butcher really deserves credit for still coming up with original and creative storylines. Like Jury Duty, which is in a setting I would never have expected, the stories show that the author is not yet done with his characters and has many more in store for the future of Harry Dresden.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I always blabber about character development. Well, what I like about these short stories is that not all are from Harry’s point of view. Instead, Butcher...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 08:35:58 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/jim-butcher-brief-cases/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/jim-butcher-brief-cases/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I've Read - November 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;missed-opportunities&quot;&gt;Missed Opportunities&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;One of the books that I wanted to read in November was &lt;em&gt;Brief Cases&lt;/em&gt;, a collection of short stories that focus on the Dresdenverse while I - like many others - am waiting for Jim Butcher to finish &lt;em&gt;Peace Talks&lt;/em&gt;. Like I said, I took a small break from reading in November but I did start this book. I will probably finish it today or tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;elevation&quot;&gt;Elevation&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Congratulations Stephen King for winning the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/choiceawards/best-horror-books-2018&quot;&gt;10th annual Goodreads Choice Awards Horror category&lt;/a&gt;! While it wasn’t my choice for the horror books, I’m still glad it showed up....</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 05:20:40 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-november-2018/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-november-2018/</guid>
        
        <category>2018</category>
        
        
        <category>Monthly Summary</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dean Koontz - The Forbidden Door</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We return to the world of Jane Hawk. After book number 3, she now has to get to her son before her enemies find him. Will she be able to do that? And what about her &lt;em&gt;followers&lt;/em&gt;? Will the people that trust her pay for that? We find out in this story.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I really liked this book. Where the third instalment let me down, this one was superb. Instead of Jane Hawk being the hunter, she is turned into the hunted. The book was written from that perspective and it gives the readers more insights in how the people hunting...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 19:28:11 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/dean-koontz-the-forbidden-door/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/dean-koontz-the-forbidden-door/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jeff Ryan - Super Mario</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This book is a treasure: it contains so many fun facts about history’s funniest - if not most famous - video game character. I have learnt so many things. Like, did you know how Mario got his name? Or when the un-official super mario holiday is? If you do, nice! If you don’t, read this book. You’ll be amazed and smiling a lot!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I’ve learnt that the strategy Nintendo used has its benefits and disadvantages. I myself don’t see me use the strategy a lot because it’s not collaborative. Yet, I understand how it made Nintendo so big and how...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 15:05:15 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/jeff-ryan-super-mario/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/jeff-ryan-super-mario/</guid>
        
        <category>Non-fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Darcy Coates - Craven Manor</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m used to psychological horror stories. You know, not necessarily the gory ones but the ones that keep you looking backwards when you walk on the street and make you hurry up when it starts to get dark. That’s the kind of horror I like. It’s also the kind of horror presented in this book, albeit at a lower level.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Craven Manor&lt;/em&gt; does not have gory elements. The story tries to scare you as well as lure you in for more. The latter it does very well: every chapter leaves you wanting to know more of the story. It’s original...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 14:49:49 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/darcy-coates-craven-manor/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/darcy-coates-craven-manor/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stephen King - Elevation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Stephen King tries to tell a compelling story on these few pages and I think you’re either completely pro or completely against. I am one of the lucky guys. I really liked it!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There’s not much space for plot twists and the story is so short that I cannot speak about predictability. By the time you could predict what was going to happen, you were already readying it. But that doesn’t have to be a bad thing.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;King touches political and humane subjects with this story, trying to show the boldness of people against same-sex marriage as well as trying...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 17:34:34 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/stephen-king-elevation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/stephen-king-elevation/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I've Read - October 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-first-days&quot;&gt;The First Days&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;The first book I read in October was a zombie horror novel. &lt;em&gt;The First Days&lt;/em&gt; was fun, but just barely. There were good things in here, but not enough to keep me reading the series.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1388800064l/9648068.jpg&quot; class=&quot;monthly-summary-summary&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you want a horror novel with a lot of w-t-f’s and some subplots that are too far-fetched too feel real, this is a book for you!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;the-only-rule-is-it-has-to-work&quot;&gt;The Only Rule Is It Has to Work&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;I found out about this book via a colleague at work. It has a lot of things that I like: there’s...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 20:52:11 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-october-2018/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-october-2018/</guid>
        
        <category>2018</category>
        
        
        <category>Monthly Summary</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Paul Woodruff - The Ajax Dilemma</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Paul Woodruff is a philosopher and this Dutch translation of his book starts with a foreword by another philosopher. I knew one thing before reading and I’ve been reminded throughout this book: I’m not a philosopher. I didn’t like the foreword. Too much terms and words too complicated for a book like this one.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Then there’s Woodruff’s work. First he explains the story about Ajax and Odysseus, filled in some gaps with some personal touches. He does this well. Also when he starts interpreting the story from a leadership point of view, he does a good job.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The last half...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 08:56:10 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/paul-woodruff-the-ajax-dilemma/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/paul-woodruff-the-ajax-dilemma/</guid>
        
        <category>Non-Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Karen M. McManus - One of Us Is Lying</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This time things are different. I like this book. Karen M. McManus is good at keeping a mystery going and I must admit, I was on a wrong path for a long time. But… I guessed correctly. Let’s just say that the title is a big hint. The title could have been &lt;em&gt;The Bayview Four&lt;/em&gt; and I would have been looking the wrong way even longer.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The author shows skills in character development, with great growth of Addy, Cooper and Nate. Bronwyn on the other hand is a girl-by-the-book. And that’s not necessarily a good thing here. She’s missing some...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 20:03:16 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/karen-m-mcmanus-one-of-us-is-lying/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/karen-m-mcmanus-one-of-us-is-lying/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Adam Alter - Irresistible: The Rise of Addictive Technology and the Business of Keeping Us Hooked</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After the first chapter, I had my doubts. I seriously thought I wouldn’t finish this book. The first chapter made it look like this book was going to be nothing but bitching on technology.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Thank goodness it was not. Instead, the book is filled with a lot of knowledge and nice-to-know facts. But I haven’t really learnt a lot of interesting things. Nothing that I can use directly in my life, anyway.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The content of this book is right: if you’re easily addicted you can get into trouble easily with current technology and gadgets. If you have enough common sense,...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 22:27:06 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/adam-alter-irresistible/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/adam-alter-irresistible/</guid>
        
        <category>Non-Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A.M. Khalifa - Terminal Rage</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot going on in this book. From a terrorist hostage situation to an Egyptian prison worse than Guantanamo and a torture van in London. Anything you’d want from a thriller is in this book. Except maybe a few things.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But before I get to those, here’s some praise. Khalifa has done a great job with the character development in this book. I love how Alexander and Sam develop. It’s very hard to find out which of them is the protagonist in this novel. That’s meant as a compliment: it’s a job well done.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Also, the plot twists take...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 10:55:01 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/am-khalifa-terminal-rage/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/am-khalifa-terminal-rage/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ben Lindbergh &amp; Sam Miller - The Only Rule Is It Has to Work</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Data: that’s basically what this book is about. Can you create a good team, in this case a good baseball team, by choosing players based on data? That’s the experiment Ben Lindbergh and Sam Miller wanted to do. When the opportunity arrived, they said “yes” immediately. But there’s a catch.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;First of all, they were promised to have full say in the choosing of the players. Yet, they only had a small role. They found about one third of the players their team would eventually have. Then they were too nervous to interact with their coach, letting him leave their...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 10:34:09 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/ben-lindbergh-sam-miller-the-only-rule-is-it-has-to-work/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/ben-lindbergh-sam-miller-the-only-rule-is-it-has-to-work/</guid>
        
        <category>Non-Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rhiannon Frater - The First Days</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The premise of the story is the well known zombie apocalypse plot. A zombie breakout occurs, people get eaten while others survive. Mostly those with guns tend to survive. People start making small communities in order to defend better against the growing population of undead.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This book makes it all too unbelievable. The actions that people do, the way they behave. It makes almost no sense. What I missed in this book was some explanation on how the zombie apocalypse started. This information is not provided. Probably because it would be too unbelievable…&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You see the characters develop throughout this...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 11:57:51 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/rhiannon-frater-the-first-days/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/rhiannon-frater-the-first-days/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I've Read - September 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;missed-opportunities&quot;&gt;Missed Opportunities&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;I’ve started reading about &lt;em&gt;The Ajax Dilemma&lt;/em&gt; and I’ve also finished &lt;em&gt;The First Days&lt;/em&gt; by now. I didn’t get to &lt;em&gt;Confessions of a D-List Supervillain&lt;/em&gt; and that’s not going to change soon. I’ve had enough of superhero stories for a while!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;no-turning-back&quot;&gt;No Turning Back&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;A bunch of friends get together for a diabolical plan that will turn their lives upside down. A book filled with a predictable if not likable story. That’s the summary of &lt;em&gt;No Turning Back&lt;/em&gt; if you ask me!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1356125419l/9393062.jpg&quot; class=&quot;monthly-summary-summary&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I’ve read some Marcus Sakey books before and I must...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 20:00:10 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-september-2018/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-september-2018/</guid>
        
        <category>2018</category>
        
        
        <category>Monthly Summary</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Peter Brown - Make It Stick</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I started reading &lt;em&gt;Make It Stick&lt;/em&gt; because of a mistake… I actually wanted to read a different book with almost the same name. But I wasn’t too late when I realized that. I read the synopsis and decided to give this book a try anyway. I’m really happy that I did.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Although the book was a bit too long for me and had too much detail on education, I liked it a lot. It got me thinking. At all important jobs, people prepare before they perform. So why are software developers (and others) expected to perform eight hours per day...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 20:24:21 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/peter-brown-make-it-stick/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/peter-brown-make-it-stick/</guid>
        
        <category>Non-Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Marcus Sakey - No Turning Back</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a fun story. Really, have you ever thought about four normal people, without any criminal record, deciding to go for a robbery? Not just a robbery. One that is safe. One that can’t go wrong! The story evolves in many ways and leaves you turning page after page quicker and quicker.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What I liked a lot was the character development in this book. The main characters all change from the first to the last page, in a good way. They don’t just act differently. You can see in their actions and thoughts that they’ve become different people. Sakey...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 18:37:22 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/marcus-sakey-no-turning-back/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/marcus-sakey-no-turning-back/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I've Read - August 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;missed-opportunities&quot;&gt;Missed Opportunities&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;When I last wrote a Monthly Summary, I was hoping to read &lt;em&gt;No Turning Back&lt;/em&gt; by Marcus Sakey. I didn’t get to that book in time, although I’m already at page 150 as of writing this blog post. Instead, I went for &lt;em&gt;Station Eleven&lt;/em&gt;. Sadly enough.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;the-outsider&quot;&gt;The Outsider&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;This long book is the last one Stephen King has written to date. And boy, does he know his skills. From the first paragraph to the last word, he can keep you turning pages until your fingers go numb. It’s such a relief to see that the old...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 11:58:43 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-august-2018/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-august-2018/</guid>
        
        <category>2018</category>
        
        
        <category>Monthly Summary</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Martha Alderson - The Plot Whisperer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was eager to read this book and had high expectations. Expectations that were almost destroyed by the first topic in the book. The so-called &lt;b&gt;Universal Story&lt;/b&gt; theory is not something that I liked reading about because I simply don’t believe in it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That being said, after bearing with Martha Alderson and finishing her book, I get what she’s saying. Sometimes a story can feel like the way it is written is the way it &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; to be written. And when you get that feeling, that is the feeling of the Universal Story. Because every story can be written with...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 19:07:52 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/martha-alderson-the-plot-whisperer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/martha-alderson-the-plot-whisperer/</guid>
        
        <category>Non-fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scott Meyer - Out of Spite, Out of Mind</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Before I start this review, I want to point out that before reading this book I had just finished &lt;em&gt;Station Eleven&lt;/em&gt; which I didn’t like at all. The last Magic 2.0 book I’d read was &lt;em&gt;Fight and Flight&lt;/em&gt; and I didn’t find it great either.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So was I happy when I started reading &lt;em&gt;Out of Spite, Out of Mind&lt;/em&gt;! Boy, this book has it all. At the first chapter, it is made clear what the goal is. Even though we don’t actually know the problem, it’s clear something needs to be done. And to do that, we go on this...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 12:08:05 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/scott-meyer-out-of-spite-out-of-mind/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/scott-meyer-out-of-spite-out-of-mind/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sad but True</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Due to a lot of things asking a lot of time, I’m putting the writing posts on hold for a while. I already know I will not be able to maintain the 1 story per week rhythm so I might as well let you know upfront. I’ll try to chime in a creative writing once in a while, but don’t be surprised if nothing new gets posted here for weeks. I will try to add book reviews though, as I hope to still read during the coming period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your patience!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 12:59:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/sad-but-true/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/sad-but-true/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Creative Writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
