<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The wel_ko blog | A blog about reading, writing and the like.</title>
    <description>A blog where I review books, try to report on my progress as a writer and generally add other ramblings that come to mind.</description>
    <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://thewelkoblog.xyz/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 19:45:28 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 19:45:28 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dean Koontz - The Forbidden Door</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We return to the world of Jane Hawk. After book number 3, she now has to get to her son before her enemies find him. Will she be able to do that? And what about her &lt;em&gt;followers&lt;/em&gt;? Will the people that trust her pay for that? We find out in this story.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I really liked this book. Where the third instalment let me down, this one was superb. Instead of Jane Hawk being the hunter, she is turned into the hunted. The book was written from that perspective and it gives the readers more insights in how the people hunting...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 19:28:11 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/dean-koontz-the-forbidden-door/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/dean-koontz-the-forbidden-door/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jeff Ryan - Super Mario</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This book is a treasure: it contains so many fun facts about history’s funniest - if not most famous - video game character. I have learnt so many things. Like, did you know how Mario got his name? Or when the un-official super mario holiday is? If you do, nice! If you don’t, read this book. You’ll be amazed and smiling a lot!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I’ve learnt that the strategy Nintendo used has its benefits and disadvantages. I myself don’t see me use the strategy a lot because it’s not collaborative. Yet, I understand how it made Nintendo so big and how...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 15:05:15 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/jeff-ryan-super-mario/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/jeff-ryan-super-mario/</guid>
        
        <category>Non-fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Darcy Coates - Craven Manor</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m used to psychological horror stories. You know, not necessarily the gory ones but the ones that keep you looking backwards when you walk on the street and make you hurry up when it starts to get dark. That’s the kind of horror I like. It’s also the kind of horror presented in this book, albeit at a lower level.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Craven Manor&lt;/em&gt; does not have gory elements. The story tries to scare you as well as lure you in for more. The latter it does very well: every chapter leaves you wanting to know more of the story. It’s original...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 14:49:49 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/darcy-coates-craven-manor/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/darcy-coates-craven-manor/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stephen King - Elevation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Stephen King tries to tell a compelling story on these few pages and I think you’re either completely pro or completely against. I am one of the lucky guys. I really liked it!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There’s not much space for plot twists and the story is so short that I cannot speak about predictability. By the time you could predict what was going to happen, you were already readying it. But that doesn’t have to be a bad thing.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;King touches political and humane subjects with this story, trying to show the boldness of people against same-sex marriage as well as trying...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 17:34:34 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/stephen-king-elevation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/stephen-king-elevation/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I've Read - October 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-first-days&quot;&gt;The First Days&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;The first book I read in October was a zombie horror novel. &lt;em&gt;The First Days&lt;/em&gt; was fun, but just barely. There were good things in here, but not enough to keep me reading the series.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1388800064l/9648068.jpg&quot; class=&quot;monthly-summary-summary&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you want a horror novel with a lot of w-t-f’s and some subplots that are too far-fetched too feel real, this is a book for you!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;the-only-rule-is-it-has-to-work&quot;&gt;The Only Rule Is It Has to Work&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;I found out about this book via a colleague at work. It has a lot of things that I like: there’s...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 20:52:11 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-october-2018/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-october-2018/</guid>
        
        <category>2018</category>
        
        
        <category>Monthly Summary</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Paul Woodruff - The Ajax Dilemma</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Paul Woodruff is a philosopher and this Dutch translation of his book starts with a foreword by another philosopher. I knew one thing before reading and I’ve been reminded throughout this book: I’m not a philosopher. I didn’t like the foreword. Too much terms and words too complicated for a book like this one.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Then there’s Woodruff’s work. First he explains the story about Ajax and Odysseus, filled in some gaps with some personal touches. He does this well. Also when he starts interpreting the story from a leadership point of view, he does a good job.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The last half...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 08:56:10 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/paul-woodruff-the-ajax-dilemma/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/paul-woodruff-the-ajax-dilemma/</guid>
        
        <category>Non-Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Karen M. McManus - One of Us Is Lying</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This time things are different. I like this book. Karen M. McManus is good at keeping a mystery going and I must admit, I was on a wrong path for a long time. But… I guessed correctly. Let’s just say that the title is a big hint. The title could have been &lt;em&gt;The Bayview Four&lt;/em&gt; and I would have been looking the wrong way even longer.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The author shows skills in character development, with great growth of Addy, Cooper and Nate. Bronwyn on the other hand is a girl-by-the-book. And that’s not necessarily a good thing here. She’s missing some...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 20:03:16 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/karen-m-mcmanus-one-of-us-is-lying/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/karen-m-mcmanus-one-of-us-is-lying/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Adam Alter - Irresistible: The Rise of Addictive Technology and the Business of Keeping Us Hooked</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After the first chapter, I had my doubts. I seriously thought I wouldn’t finish this book. The first chapter made it look like this book was going to be nothing but bitching on technology.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Thank goodness it was not. Instead, the book is filled with a lot of knowledge and nice-to-know facts. But I haven’t really learnt a lot of interesting things. Nothing that I can use directly in my life, anyway.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The content of this book is right: if you’re easily addicted you can get into trouble easily with current technology and gadgets. If you have enough common sense,...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 22:27:06 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/adam-alter-irresistible/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/adam-alter-irresistible/</guid>
        
        <category>Non-Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A.M. Khalifa - Terminal Rage</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot going on in this book. From a terrorist hostage situation to an Egyptian prison worse than Guantanamo and a torture van in London. Anything you’d want from a thriller is in this book. Except maybe a few things.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But before I get to those, here’s some praise. Khalifa has done a great job with the character development in this book. I love how Alexander and Sam develop. It’s very hard to find out which of them is the protagonist in this novel. That’s meant as a compliment: it’s a job well done.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Also, the plot twists take...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 10:55:01 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/am-khalifa-terminal-rage/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/am-khalifa-terminal-rage/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ben Lindbergh &amp; Sam Miller - The Only Rule Is It Has to Work</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Data: that’s basically what this book is about. Can you create a good team, in this case a good baseball team, by choosing players based on data? That’s the experiment Ben Lindbergh and Sam Miller wanted to do. When the opportunity arrived, they said “yes” immediately. But there’s a catch.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;First of all, they were promised to have full say in the choosing of the players. Yet, they only had a small role. They found about one third of the players their team would eventually have. Then they were too nervous to interact with their coach, letting him leave their...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 10:34:09 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/ben-lindbergh-sam-miller-the-only-rule-is-it-has-to-work/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/ben-lindbergh-sam-miller-the-only-rule-is-it-has-to-work/</guid>
        
        <category>Non-Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rhiannon Frater - The First Days</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The premise of the story is the well known zombie apocalypse plot. A zombie breakout occurs, people get eaten while others survive. Mostly those with guns tend to survive. People start making small communities in order to defend better against the growing population of undead.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This book makes it all too unbelievable. The actions that people do, the way they behave. It makes almost no sense. What I missed in this book was some explanation on how the zombie apocalypse started. This information is not provided. Probably because it would be too unbelievable…&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You see the characters develop throughout this...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 11:57:51 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/rhiannon-frater-the-first-days/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/rhiannon-frater-the-first-days/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I've Read - September 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;missed-opportunities&quot;&gt;Missed Opportunities&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;I’ve started reading about &lt;em&gt;The Ajax Dilemma&lt;/em&gt; and I’ve also finished &lt;em&gt;The First Days&lt;/em&gt; by now. I didn’t get to &lt;em&gt;Confessions of a D-List Supervillain&lt;/em&gt; and that’s not going to change soon. I’ve had enough of superhero stories for a while!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;no-turning-back&quot;&gt;No Turning Back&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;A bunch of friends get together for a diabolical plan that will turn their lives upside down. A book filled with a predictable if not likable story. That’s the summary of &lt;em&gt;No Turning Back&lt;/em&gt; if you ask me!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1356125419l/9393062.jpg&quot; class=&quot;monthly-summary-summary&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I’ve read some Marcus Sakey books before and I must...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 20:00:10 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-september-2018/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-september-2018/</guid>
        
        <category>2018</category>
        
        
        <category>Monthly Summary</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Peter Brown - Make It Stick</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I started reading &lt;em&gt;Make It Stick&lt;/em&gt; because of a mistake… I actually wanted to read a different book with almost the same name. But I wasn’t too late when I realized that. I read the synopsis and decided to give this book a try anyway. I’m really happy that I did.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Although the book was a bit too long for me and had too much detail on education, I liked it a lot. It got me thinking. At all important jobs, people prepare before they perform. So why are software developers (and others) expected to perform eight hours per day...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 20:24:21 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/peter-brown-make-it-stick/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/peter-brown-make-it-stick/</guid>
        
        <category>Non-Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Marcus Sakey - No Turning Back</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a fun story. Really, have you ever thought about four normal people, without any criminal record, deciding to go for a robbery? Not just a robbery. One that is safe. One that can’t go wrong! The story evolves in many ways and leaves you turning page after page quicker and quicker.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What I liked a lot was the character development in this book. The main characters all change from the first to the last page, in a good way. They don’t just act differently. You can see in their actions and thoughts that they’ve become different people. Sakey...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 18:37:22 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/marcus-sakey-no-turning-back/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/marcus-sakey-no-turning-back/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I've Read - August 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;missed-opportunities&quot;&gt;Missed Opportunities&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;When I last wrote a Monthly Summary, I was hoping to read &lt;em&gt;No Turning Back&lt;/em&gt; by Marcus Sakey. I didn’t get to that book in time, although I’m already at page 150 as of writing this blog post. Instead, I went for &lt;em&gt;Station Eleven&lt;/em&gt;. Sadly enough.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;the-outsider&quot;&gt;The Outsider&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;This long book is the last one Stephen King has written to date. And boy, does he know his skills. From the first paragraph to the last word, he can keep you turning pages until your fingers go numb. It’s such a relief to see that the old...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 11:58:43 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-august-2018/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-august-2018/</guid>
        
        <category>2018</category>
        
        
        <category>Monthly Summary</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Martha Alderson - The Plot Whisperer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was eager to read this book and had high expectations. Expectations that were almost destroyed by the first topic in the book. The so-called &lt;b&gt;Universal Story&lt;/b&gt; theory is not something that I liked reading about because I simply don’t believe in it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That being said, after bearing with Martha Alderson and finishing her book, I get what she’s saying. Sometimes a story can feel like the way it is written is the way it &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; to be written. And when you get that feeling, that is the feeling of the Universal Story. Because every story can be written with...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 19:07:52 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/martha-alderson-the-plot-whisperer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/martha-alderson-the-plot-whisperer/</guid>
        
        <category>Non-fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scott Meyer - Out of Spite, Out of Mind</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Before I start this review, I want to point out that before reading this book I had just finished &lt;em&gt;Station Eleven&lt;/em&gt; which I didn’t like at all. The last Magic 2.0 book I’d read was &lt;em&gt;Fight and Flight&lt;/em&gt; and I didn’t find it great either.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So was I happy when I started reading &lt;em&gt;Out of Spite, Out of Mind&lt;/em&gt;! Boy, this book has it all. At the first chapter, it is made clear what the goal is. Even though we don’t actually know the problem, it’s clear something needs to be done. And to do that, we go on this...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 12:08:05 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/scott-meyer-out-of-spite-out-of-mind/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/scott-meyer-out-of-spite-out-of-mind/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sad but True</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Due to a lot of things asking a lot of time, I’m putting the writing posts on hold for a while. I already know I will not be able to maintain the 1 story per week rhythm so I might as well let you know upfront. I’ll try to chime in a creative writing once in a while, but don’t be surprised if nothing new gets posted here for weeks. I will try to add book reviews though, as I hope to still read during the coming period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your patience!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 12:59:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/sad-but-true/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/sad-but-true/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Creative Writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Emily St. John Mandel - Station Eleven</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m reading some books about writing so I get some of the stuff writers need to do. This also means that I spot missing information or flaws quite fast. As I did in this book. It was quite sad, actually.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The book starts with chapters that seem hardly connected. Okay, there’s a link: all the ‘main’ characters seem to know Arthur Leander. But that’s it! For me it would be great after the first number of chapters, what the goal of the book is. Is the goal to survive? To find someone? To help someone or fix something? I had...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 18:30:34 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-emily-st-john-mandel-station-eleven/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-emily-st-john-mandel-station-eleven/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dancing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The music was very loud. The DJ had put on a pop song and some people were dancing to it. Not us though. We were standing at the counter, talking about nonsense and making stupid jokes. Just smalltalk. I mostly nodded my hand and smiled.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I did my best not to look at Suzannah all the time but it was hard. She was wearing the most beautiful dress I’d ever seen. We were nineteen and I’d been running around with this crush for her for four years now. From the day that we met, I felt there was something special...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 09:31:12 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/dancing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/dancing/</guid>
        
        <category>Dancing</category>
        
        <category>Love</category>
        
        <category>Romance</category>
        
        
        <category>Creative Writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: C.T. Phipps - The Science of Supervillainy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We start the fourth book of this series right after the disappointing ending of the previous book. The author even had a comment on that.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Willowhugger/status/1017505790628900864&quot;&gt;“I’m man enough to admit the book needed a different ending and probably another third to deal with President Omega.” - C.T. Phipps on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;President Omega is dealt with alright. Maybe a bit too soon, but it’s rather clear that he was just a very minor character in this book. At the time the evil president got defeated, I was still wearing my sceptic glasses. I missed a bit of action....</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 09:22:41 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-c-t-phipps-the-science-of-supervillainy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-c-t-phipps-the-science-of-supervillainy/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: Nicole Forsgren, Jez Humble &amp; Gene Kim - Accelerate</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The foreword, written by Martin Fowler, explains the concern I’ve had about many articles over the last years. People tell us what they’ve learnt but not how they’ve learnt it. See it as a form of deliberate partial transparency. This book tries to provide a more open form of the research the authors have provided over the past years.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The first part is more about doing software projects the &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; way. The authors explain a lot of DevOps techniques I believe in as well as mention the strategies they believe provide the best outcome for a software project. In most...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 08:41:33 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-nicole-forsgren-jez-humble-gene-kim-accelerate/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-nicole-forsgren-jez-humble-gene-kim-accelerate/</guid>
        
        <category>Non-Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: Stephen King - The Outsider</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Stephen King has improved his writing a lot over the last decades. I remember reading some stories and loving the beginning and end, but hating the middle parts because they were boring. Instead of that, &lt;em&gt;The Outsider&lt;/em&gt; keeps you turning pages time and time again.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He is a master at character development. He is a master of suspense. I can only think of one flaw for this book: I want to know more about the Outsider. We’re left with some questions - as King points out via the voice of his characters. But this is just a minor flaw. I...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 11:00:34 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-stephen-king-the-outsider/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-stephen-king-the-outsider/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Vessel</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Rick Menzou walked through the forest. He had wandered off from the group but that was alright. These days, scouts groups didn’t need to stay in close contact. They could use GPS tags in their suits to find each other. If that would be necessary.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Rick, whom the others sometimes called &lt;em&gt;Mezzou&lt;/em&gt;, wasn’t really looking for something. He liked being an adventurer and hoped to one day join the expeditions himself, just like his father. But instead of walking foreign lands and discovering new places to habit humans, Rick was stuck on Powell 5. There was nothing on this planet...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 09:31:12 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/the-vessel/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/the-vessel/</guid>
        
        <category>Spaceship</category>
        
        <category>Adventure</category>
        
        <category>Expedition</category>
        
        <category>Confusion</category>
        
        
        <category>Creative Writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I've Read - July 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;missed-opportunities&quot;&gt;Missed Opportunities&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are three unfinished books that I mentioned last time. &lt;em&gt;Station Eleven&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Devourer&lt;/em&gt; are two books I didn’t get to start yet. I did start &lt;em&gt;The Plot Whisperer&lt;/em&gt;, but I’m only one quarter in yet. Instead, I read &lt;em&gt;Black Box Thinking&lt;/em&gt; and I started Stephen King’s latest, &lt;em&gt;The Outsider&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;the-crooked-staircase&quot;&gt;The Crooked Staircase&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;I started the month reading &lt;em&gt;The Crooked Staircase&lt;/em&gt;. This is the third book of the Jane Hawk series. If you want to read this one, it’s advised that you read the first two books of the series. You better do, because they’re...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 19:56:19 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-july-2018/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-july-2018/</guid>
        
        <category>2018</category>
        
        
        <category>Monthly Summary</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bye-bye Wordpress</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-the-big-change&quot;&gt;Why the big change?&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Because I’ve had two blogs for quite some time now. There’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://readingwithwelko.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;my reading blog&lt;/a&gt;, where I review books and discuss other book-ish matters, and there’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://welkoiswriting.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;my writing blog&lt;/a&gt;, where I talk about writing and try to post short stories whenever possible. So as you may or may not know, I am maintaining two blogs at the moment.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And that just makes no sense. Why would I keep you away from content? Instead, I want feedback and opinions. So it’s in my interest to get as much content as possible over to you! One...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 20:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/bye-bye-wordpress/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/bye-bye-wordpress/</guid>
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>Github Pages</category>
        
        <category>Wordpress</category>
        
        <category>Blog</category>
        
        
        <category>Changes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Unrequited Love Poem</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I forgot to ask something in my last post. If you have any feedback, please leave a comment below the stories! Anything is useful. I’d love to hear what you think.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;She closed the book. After reading the poem, she was certain. She had never seen the words so clear before. She was trapped in a marriage with a man she didn’t love anymore. It’s been that way for a long time now.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;She decided for herself that the moment had come to express her feelings. To explain her thoughts and to make it very, very clear. It was time...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 19:44:45 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/the-unrequited-love-poem/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/the-unrequited-love-poem/</guid>
        
        <category>Breakup</category>
        
        <category>Love</category>
        
        <category>Memories</category>
        
        <category>Romance</category>
        
        <category>Writing</category>
        
        <category>Creative Writing</category>
        
        
        <category>Creative Writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: S.J. Delos - So Not a Hero</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Wow. There are many treasures in this book. Well written emotional scenes. Multiple sex scenes, some more explicit than others. And a superhero battle to lick your fingers clean. But there’s a problem. While I understand all those different scenes can be useful in a superhero book, I would expect a lot more of the superhero battles. And there is only one.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Instead, this book focuses on a very sexist way of looking at the protagonist. She is an enhanced woman who looks and acts like a sex object. So do all the other women she interacts with – except...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 21:26:27 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-s-j-delos-so-not-a-hero/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-s-j-delos-so-not-a-hero/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Outside the Window</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It was a beautiful spring morning. I was looking outside when I heard a yell come from the back door. At first I didn’t want to go and look. Not after the sounds I had heard the previous night. The yelling persisted, so I dragged myself out of the bed and went downstairs.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I strode to the back door as quiet as I could. I had left my slippers upstairs, hoping my bare feet wouldn’t give me away. When I came close to the door, the yelling stopped. I stood still.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;After a few minutes of dead silence, I took...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 06:07:33 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/outside-the-window/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/outside-the-window/</guid>
        
        <category>Anxiety</category>
        
        <category>Mental health</category>
        
        <category>Writing</category>
        
        
        <category>Creative Writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: Matthew Syed - Black Box Thinking</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As the author explains, &lt;em&gt;Black Box Thinking&lt;/em&gt; is not about thinking about certain things as ‘black boxes’, things that we don’t know (or want to know) the internals from. Instead, it’s an analogy to the aviation sector, where black boxes are used to learn and improve the flight processes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Matthew Syed brings up examples in a way that many fiction artists are jealous of. He builds his story perfectly and brings up tension in the right places. What’s even better, next to the many examples he tells a story about himself. How Matthew himself is human and thus susceptible to making...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 08:07:48 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-matthew-syed-black-box-thinking/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-matthew-syed-black-box-thinking/</guid>
        
        <category>Non-Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
