<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The wel_ko blog | A blog about reading, writing and the like.</title>
    <description>A blog where I review books, try to report on my progress as a writer and generally add other ramblings that come to mind.</description>
    <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://thewelkoblog.xyz/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 18:57:29 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 18:57:29 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Marcus Sakey - No Turning Back</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a fun story. Really, have you ever thought about four normal people, without any criminal record, deciding to go for a robbery? Not just a robbery. One that is safe. One that can’t go wrong! The story evolves in many ways and leaves you turning page after page quicker and quicker.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What I liked a lot was the character development in this book. The main characters all change from the first to the last page, in a good way. They don’t just act differently. You can see in their actions and thoughts that they’ve become different people. Sakey...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 18:37:22 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/marcus-sakey-no-turning-back/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/marcus-sakey-no-turning-back/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I've Read - August 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;missed-opportunities&quot;&gt;Missed Opportunities&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;When I last wrote a Monthly Summary, I was hoping to read &lt;em&gt;No Turning Back&lt;/em&gt; by Marcus Sakey. I didn’t get to that book in time, although I’m already at page 150 as of writing this blog post. Instead, I went for &lt;em&gt;Station Eleven&lt;/em&gt;. Sadly enough.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;the-outsider&quot;&gt;The Outsider&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;This long book is the last one Stephen King has written to date. And boy, does he know his skills. From the first paragraph to the last word, he can keep you turning pages until your fingers go numb. It’s such a relief to see that the old...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 11:58:43 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-august-2018/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-august-2018/</guid>
        
        <category>2018</category>
        
        
        <category>Monthly Summary</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Martha Alderson - The Plot Whisperer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was eager to read this book and had high expectations. Expectations that were almost destroyed by the first topic in the book. The so-called &lt;b&gt;Universal Story&lt;/b&gt; theory is not something that I liked reading about because I simply don’t believe in it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That being said, after bearing with Martha Alderson and finishing her book, I get what she’s saying. Sometimes a story can feel like the way it is written is the way it &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; to be written. And when you get that feeling, that is the feeling of the Universal Story. Because every story can be written with...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 19:07:52 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/martha-alderson-the-plot-whisperer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/martha-alderson-the-plot-whisperer/</guid>
        
        <category>Non-fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scott Meyer - Out of Spite, Out of Mind</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Before I start this review, I want to point out that before reading this book I had just finished &lt;em&gt;Station Eleven&lt;/em&gt; which I didn’t like at all. The last Magic 2.0 book I’d read was &lt;em&gt;Fight and Flight&lt;/em&gt; and I didn’t find it great either.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So was I happy when I started reading &lt;em&gt;Out of Spite, Out of Mind&lt;/em&gt;! Boy, this book has it all. At the first chapter, it is made clear what the goal is. Even though we don’t actually know the problem, it’s clear something needs to be done. And to do that, we go on this...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 12:08:05 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/scott-meyer-out-of-spite-out-of-mind/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/scott-meyer-out-of-spite-out-of-mind/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sad but True</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Due to a lot of things asking a lot of time, I’m putting the writing posts on hold for a while. I already know I will not be able to maintain the 1 story per week rhythm so I might as well let you know upfront. I’ll try to chime in a creative writing once in a while, but don’t be surprised if nothing new gets posted here for weeks. I will try to add book reviews though, as I hope to still read during the coming period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your patience!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 12:59:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/sad-but-true/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/sad-but-true/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Creative Writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Emily St. John Mandel - Station Eleven</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m reading some books about writing so I get some of the stuff writers need to do. This also means that I spot missing information or flaws quite fast. As I did in this book. It was quite sad, actually.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The book starts with chapters that seem hardly connected. Okay, there’s a link: all the ‘main’ characters seem to know Arthur Leander. But that’s it! For me it would be great after the first number of chapters, what the goal of the book is. Is the goal to survive? To find someone? To help someone or fix something? I had...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 18:30:34 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-emily-st-john-mandel-station-eleven/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-emily-st-john-mandel-station-eleven/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dancing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The music was very loud. The DJ had put on a pop song and some people were dancing to it. Not us though. We were standing at the counter, talking about nonsense and making stupid jokes. Just smalltalk. I mostly nodded my hand and smiled.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I did my best not to look at Suzannah all the time but it was hard. She was wearing the most beautiful dress I’d ever seen. We were nineteen and I’d been running around with this crush for her for four years now. From the day that we met, I felt there was something special...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 09:31:12 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/dancing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/dancing/</guid>
        
        <category>Dancing</category>
        
        <category>Love</category>
        
        <category>Romance</category>
        
        
        <category>Creative Writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: C.T. Phipps - The Science of Supervillainy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We start the fourth book of this series right after the disappointing ending of the previous book. The author even had a comment on that.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Willowhugger/status/1017505790628900864&quot;&gt;“I’m man enough to admit the book needed a different ending and probably another third to deal with President Omega.” - C.T. Phipps on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;President Omega is dealt with alright. Maybe a bit too soon, but it’s rather clear that he was just a very minor character in this book. At the time the evil president got defeated, I was still wearing my sceptic glasses. I missed a bit of action....</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 09:22:41 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-c-t-phipps-the-science-of-supervillainy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-c-t-phipps-the-science-of-supervillainy/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: Nicole Forsgren, Jez Humble &amp; Gene Kim - Accelerate</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The foreword, written by Martin Fowler, explains the concern I’ve had about many articles over the last years. People tell us what they’ve learnt but not how they’ve learnt it. See it as a form of deliberate partial transparency. This book tries to provide a more open form of the research the authors have provided over the past years.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The first part is more about doing software projects the &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; way. The authors explain a lot of DevOps techniques I believe in as well as mention the strategies they believe provide the best outcome for a software project. In most...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 08:41:33 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-nicole-forsgren-jez-humble-gene-kim-accelerate/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-nicole-forsgren-jez-humble-gene-kim-accelerate/</guid>
        
        <category>Non-Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: Stephen King - The Outsider</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Stephen King has improved his writing a lot over the last decades. I remember reading some stories and loving the beginning and end, but hating the middle parts because they were boring. Instead of that, &lt;em&gt;The Outsider&lt;/em&gt; keeps you turning pages time and time again.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He is a master at character development. He is a master of suspense. I can only think of one flaw for this book: I want to know more about the Outsider. We’re left with some questions - as King points out via the voice of his characters. But this is just a minor flaw. I...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 11:00:34 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-stephen-king-the-outsider/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-stephen-king-the-outsider/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Vessel</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Rick Menzou walked through the forest. He had wandered off from the group but that was alright. These days, scouts groups didn’t need to stay in close contact. They could use GPS tags in their suits to find each other. If that would be necessary.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Rick, whom the others sometimes called &lt;em&gt;Mezzou&lt;/em&gt;, wasn’t really looking for something. He liked being an adventurer and hoped to one day join the expeditions himself, just like his father. But instead of walking foreign lands and discovering new places to habit humans, Rick was stuck on Powell 5. There was nothing on this planet...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 09:31:12 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/the-vessel/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/the-vessel/</guid>
        
        <category>Spaceship</category>
        
        <category>Adventure</category>
        
        <category>Expedition</category>
        
        <category>Confusion</category>
        
        
        <category>Creative Writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I've Read - July 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;missed-opportunities&quot;&gt;Missed Opportunities&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are three unfinished books that I mentioned last time. &lt;em&gt;Station Eleven&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Devourer&lt;/em&gt; are two books I didn’t get to start yet. I did start &lt;em&gt;The Plot Whisperer&lt;/em&gt;, but I’m only one quarter in yet. Instead, I read &lt;em&gt;Black Box Thinking&lt;/em&gt; and I started Stephen King’s latest, &lt;em&gt;The Outsider&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;the-crooked-staircase&quot;&gt;The Crooked Staircase&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;I started the month reading &lt;em&gt;The Crooked Staircase&lt;/em&gt;. This is the third book of the Jane Hawk series. If you want to read this one, it’s advised that you read the first two books of the series. You better do, because they’re...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 19:56:19 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-july-2018/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-july-2018/</guid>
        
        <category>2018</category>
        
        
        <category>Monthly Summary</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bye-bye Wordpress</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-the-big-change&quot;&gt;Why the big change?&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Because I’ve had two blogs for quite some time now. There’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://readingwithwelko.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;my reading blog&lt;/a&gt;, where I review books and discuss other book-ish matters, and there’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://welkoiswriting.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;my writing blog&lt;/a&gt;, where I talk about writing and try to post short stories whenever possible. So as you may or may not know, I am maintaining two blogs at the moment.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And that just makes no sense. Why would I keep you away from content? Instead, I want feedback and opinions. So it’s in my interest to get as much content as possible over to you! One...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 20:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/bye-bye-wordpress/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/bye-bye-wordpress/</guid>
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>Github Pages</category>
        
        <category>Wordpress</category>
        
        <category>Blog</category>
        
        
        <category>Changes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Unrequited Love Poem</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I forgot to ask something in my last post. If you have any feedback, please leave a comment below the stories! Anything is useful. I’d love to hear what you think.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;She closed the book. After reading the poem, she was certain. She had never seen the words so clear before. She was trapped in a marriage with a man she didn’t love anymore. It’s been that way for a long time now.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;She decided for herself that the moment had come to express her feelings. To explain her thoughts and to make it very, very clear. It was time...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 19:44:45 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/the-unrequited-love-poem/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/the-unrequited-love-poem/</guid>
        
        <category>Breakup</category>
        
        <category>Love</category>
        
        <category>Memories</category>
        
        <category>Romance</category>
        
        <category>Writing</category>
        
        <category>Creative Writing</category>
        
        
        <category>Creative Writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: S.J. Delos - So Not a Hero</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Wow. There are many treasures in this book. Well written emotional scenes. Multiple sex scenes, some more explicit than others. And a superhero battle to lick your fingers clean. But there’s a problem. While I understand all those different scenes can be useful in a superhero book, I would expect a lot more of the superhero battles. And there is only one.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Instead, this book focuses on a very sexist way of looking at the protagonist. She is an enhanced woman who looks and acts like a sex object. So do all the other women she interacts with – except...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 21:26:27 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-s-j-delos-so-not-a-hero/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-s-j-delos-so-not-a-hero/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Outside the Window</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It was a beautiful spring morning. I was looking outside when I heard a yell come from the back door. At first I didn’t want to go and look. Not after the sounds I had heard the previous night. The yelling persisted, so I dragged myself out of the bed and went downstairs.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I strode to the back door as quiet as I could. I had left my slippers upstairs, hoping my bare feet wouldn’t give me away. When I came close to the door, the yelling stopped. I stood still.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;After a few minutes of dead silence, I took...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 06:07:33 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/outside-the-window/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/outside-the-window/</guid>
        
        <category>Anxiety</category>
        
        <category>Mental health</category>
        
        <category>Writing</category>
        
        
        <category>Creative Writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: Matthew Syed - Black Box Thinking</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As the author explains, &lt;em&gt;Black Box Thinking&lt;/em&gt; is not about thinking about certain things as ‘black boxes’, things that we don’t know (or want to know) the internals from. Instead, it’s an analogy to the aviation sector, where black boxes are used to learn and improve the flight processes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Matthew Syed brings up examples in a way that many fiction artists are jealous of. He builds his story perfectly and brings up tension in the right places. What’s even better, next to the many examples he tells a story about himself. How Matthew himself is human and thus susceptible to making...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 08:07:48 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-matthew-syed-black-box-thinking/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-matthew-syed-black-box-thinking/</guid>
        
        <category>Non-Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creative Writing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a smaller setback for the book I’m writing. Long story short: I put the project on hold so that I can give it the full amount of attention it deserves. A small price for a big prize. But that doesn’t mean I want to stop writing.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;so-what-now-then&quot;&gt;So what now then?&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;I want to put my current writing project on hold but I don’t want to put writing itself on hold. So I need to find something that I can still do. Something that doesn’t take a lot of planning or time. I’ve come across this idea at...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 08:07:10 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/creative-writing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/creative-writing/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Creative Writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An A-Z Survey About Books</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I had seen the concept of an A-Z survey before but seeing it applied to books made me itch to try this out myself. So stay tuned for 26 revelations about books and me.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;author-youve-read-the-most-books-from&quot;&gt;AUTHOR YOU’VE READ THE MOST BOOKS FROM&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is not a tough question. As a teenager, I’ve spent my time reading all the books of Stephen King. Who hasn’t read books from him, right? Well, after I finished &lt;em&gt;Rage&lt;/em&gt; – which was published under his false identity Richard Bachman – I was sold. I have been a fan ever since.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I’d like to present you...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 10:07:17 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/an-a-z-survey-about-books/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/an-a-z-survey-about-books/</guid>
        
        <category>Tags</category>
        
        <category>Books</category>
        
        <category>A to Z</category>
        
        
        <category>Fun</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: C.T. Phipps - The Secrets of Supervillainy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot more time between this third book of the series and its predecessor. Which is okay. Some things happen off-screen – if you can talk about a screen here – and that’s okay as well. The sad part is that the story takes a long time to really get interesting. There’s some time catching up for what you can’t read, but then there’s just a long time of nothing really happening.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The ending of the book gets a lot better. And when you’re at the edge of your seat… the book ends. Not the story though. I guess...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 10:07:07 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-c-t-phipps-the-secrets-of-supervillainy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-c-t-phipps-the-secrets-of-supervillainy/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: Dale Carnegie - How to Win Friends and Influence People</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This book doesn’t really tell you how to win friends, but explains what behaviour causes people te like you more often. For instance, if you remember people’s names they will appreciate you more. Might sound trivial, but do we do this at all times? It’s small things like this that make other people open up to us… and how they become friends.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are a lot of tips in this book. That’s a plus, because it’s about self-improvement! But this book also has a lot of content, which makes it slow to read. I guess that’s the worst thing I...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 12:07:33 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-dale-carnegie-how-to-win-friends-and-influence-people/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-dale-carnegie-how-to-win-friends-and-influence-people/</guid>
        
        <category>Non-Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: Dean Koontz - The Crooked Staircase</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For me, up until now, this is most likely the worst book in the series. That doesn’t mean much if the other two are great of course, but still. I had a lot of troubles with this one. First off, but this is kind of nitpicking, Koontz is not the best POV writer. He tries to make you follow certain characters, which is great, but you’re more in a God-like POV. You notice things that the character you’re currently following has no way of knowing/seeing/hearing.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Where &lt;em&gt;The Whispering Room&lt;/em&gt; had a lot of stuff going on, this book actually focusses on...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 05:07:59 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-dean-koontz-the-crooked-staircase/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-dean-koontz-the-crooked-staircase/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I've Read: June 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Maybe it’s because of the books… let’s go over those!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;the-whispering-room&quot;&gt;The Whispering Room&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;I revisited the Jane Hawk series. I remember the first one being cool. A bit sci-fi, a lot of action and suspense. Yet not as good as an Orphan X book. I took this one up and was immediately happy that I did.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Whispering Room&lt;/em&gt; takes us further in the crazy story Koontz is telling. At least I hope it’s crazy… and not real. Jane Hawk is a great character and making it happen. If you’re a fan of action-packed thrillers, go read this!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 06:07:12 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-june-2018/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/what-ive-read-june-2018/</guid>
        
        <category>2018</category>
        
        
        <category>Monthly Summary</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: Cathy Yardley - Write Every Day</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Write Every Day&lt;/em&gt; does not give you writing advice. It does not focus on topics like character development or editing. Instead, it focuses on trying to write. What are things that stop you from writing? And at what moments are you able to connect the letters to form reasonable sentences? These questions are the ones you need to answer.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Crazily enough, this book reminded me about my job. In a good way. Cathy Yardley tells writers how to be agile. How to improve their process and how to remove motivation issues. That’s exactly what we want to do in the...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 08:06:22 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-cathy-yardley-write-every-day/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-cathy-yardley-write-every-day/</guid>
        
        <category>Non-Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: Dennis E. Taylor - All These Worlds</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The third instalment of the series continues the storylines that were started in &lt;em&gt;We Are Legion (We Are Bob)&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;For We Are Many&lt;/em&gt;. Taylor does a great job in giving the same guy different personalities. Because basically, the Bobs are one and the same guy. Or aren’t they? After reading the trilogy, you might not be so sure.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This book covers the biggest space war in human history. I mean human future. And the most beautiful story for an afterlife android. And the greatest search ever done (by Bender) in human history/future. And a cool story about the world’s funniest engineer.&lt;/p&gt;...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 09:06:01 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-dennis-e-taylor-all-these-worlds/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-dennis-e-taylor-all-these-worlds/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: C. T. Phipps - The Games of Supervillainy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Games of Supervillainy&lt;/em&gt; takes off immediately after the events of &lt;em&gt;The Rules of Supervillainy&lt;/em&gt;. The humour and style remain the same. That means it’s hilarious! It feels like these books are getting better and better. I can’t wait to read the next one!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A quick note on the importance of chapter titles. C. T. Phipps shows that good chapter titles really add value. Often, I’m already laughing before I read the chapter. Good job, man. Good job.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This book had everything I wanted. Even the ending was great. I haven’t felt so much emotions together with a ridiculous character in...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 08:06:43 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-c-t-phipps-the-games-of-supervillainy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-c-t-phipps-the-games-of-supervillainy/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: Dennis E. Taylor - For We Are Many</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This book takes off immediately after the events of &lt;em&gt;We Are Legion (We Are Bob)&lt;/em&gt;. The humour in this books doesn’t seem to get old. The names the Bobs choose, the jokes they make, the sarcasm. It’s all great! I’ve had many moments where I literally laughed out loud. People stare at you when you do that in public. Strange.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What I disliked about the first instalment of the series was that it was getting hard to follow. Somehow I did not have that problem in this book. Am I more used to Bob-skipping? Did Dennis E. Taylor build it up...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 11:06:02 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-dennis-e-taylor-for-we-are-many/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-dennis-e-taylor-for-we-are-many/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: Eric Barker - Barking Up the Wrong Tree</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Eric Barker does a good job at keeping you focused on what he’s saying. There’s a lot of stories, anecdotes and examples in this book to emphasise what he means. There’s some jokes here too. They keep the book playful and interesting.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The message that Barker gives you is strong. It opens up your mind to take things into account. Should you grit or should you quit? Immediately after I finished this book, I started measuring my time to see where I needed to quit. Surprisingly, it helped me.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I liked this book. It was well written, fun to read...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 03:06:05 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-eric-barker-barking-up-the-wrong-tree/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-eric-barker-barking-up-the-wrong-tree/</guid>
        
        <category>Non-Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: Sam Newman - Building Microservices</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Newman starts his book by giving his view on software development and why he doesn’t like the term software architects. This already shows that the man has got it right. He then explains microservices, the ideas behind them and how to build them in a correct way.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are so many useful references in this book. While there aren’t that much code examples, which is okay given the topics Newman touches, you get a good idea of what needs to be done. At the end, the book seems to read less smooth than in the beginning.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;“Change is inevitable....</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 06:06:26 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-sam-newman-building-microservices/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-sam-newman-building-microservices/</guid>
        
        <category>Non-Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: C. T. Phipps - The Rules of Supervillainy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The first part of this series, which becomes clear by the loose ends left dangling throughout the story, contains a well-told origin story of Merciless, the supervillain without mercy. While in some books the loose ends can be annoying, they didn’t bother me here at all. Probably because so much was happening at a fast pace, or because the book was really funny. Or both.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The character Merciless likes to make fan of its own genre. He points out the historically grown flaws in his fellow villains and his opposing heroes. Deadpool much? It’s getting close. As a fan of...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 08:06:04 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-c-t-phipps-the-rules-of-supervillainy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewelkoblog.xyz/review-c-t-phipps-the-rules-of-supervillainy/</guid>
        
        <category>Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
